人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
■
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
翻译：Iz    萌Su    小糯
校对：小糯          总监   小萌
时间轴：今        后期：加森
《开心汉堡店》
第三季第六集
莫特  你点的是小杯吗
So, Mort, you ordered a small?
-小杯有多小  -什么
- How small was it? - What?
抱歉  我正在学单人喜剧表演
Sorry, I'm taking a stand-up comedy class.
肯定是哪句没说对
I think I did something wrong.
我觉得挺逗的
I thought it was funny.
冰淇淋机又卡住了
Ugh, the ice cream machine's stuck again.
莫特  你能蹭份中杯的了
Hey, Mort, you're getting a free medium.
大杯的  超大杯的
A free large. A free extra large.
你得敲对地方  老爸
You got to hit it just right, dad.
我说了要敲对地方
I said just right!
好了孩子们  只能这样了
Okay, kids, only one thing to do,
早午餐吃冰淇淋吧
ice cream for brunch.
-太好了  -免费的冰淇淋
- Yeah, all right! - Yeah, free ice cream!
耶
Yeah.
我来把插头拔掉
Let's just unplug it.
手伸到后面去  抓住插头
Reach behind there and grab the plug.
我找到了我的牙套
I found my retainer.
你根本就不戴牙套
You don't wear a retainer.
天哪  你说得对
Oh, God, you're right!
快从我嘴里滚出去
Get it out of my mouth!
算了  我自己来
Never mind, I got it.
雨果  希望你不是来蹭冰淇淋的
Hi, Hugo, hope you're not here for ice cream.
我无法忍受甜食  琳达
I'm lactose intolerant, Linda.
我也无法忍受
I'm also intolerant of
门外那辆可疑的自行车  鲍勃
that suspicious-looking bicycle outside, Bob.
你干嘛跟我说
Uh, why are you telling me?
因为你是这个街区的监管员
Maybe it's because you're the Block Captain.
可你根本就不住在这个街区
But you don't even live on this block.
我住在这个街区的四分之一
Well, I live in the quadrant
而我恰巧是这四分之一街区的监管员
and I happen to be the Quadrant Captain.
四分之一街区监管员
Quadrant Captain.
这是你瞎编的吗
Did you make that up?
难道这些名片也能瞎编出来吗
Did I make up these Quadrant Captain business cards?
你干嘛弄一地
Why would you do that?
我不是有意的
I didn't actually mean to.
那就捡起来
Well, pick them up.
不  先别卖汉堡了
No, now stand down.
那辆车已经晾在那里24个小时了
That bike has been there for 24 hours
车座也没了
and the seat's missing.
很显然是没人要的
It's clearly abandoned.
好吧  我去处理
Fine, I'll take care of it.
别自以为是  鲍勃  快点照做
Don't be block-cocky, Bob, just do it.
你个混蛋
Jerk.
摆平他了
Nailed him.
你想偷车不成
You trying to steal my bike?
不  有人以为它是...
No, someone thought it was, um...
这是我的  想看收据吗
It's mine. Want to see the receipt?
-那不是收据  -你在哪买的
- That's not a receipt. - Where do you shop?
我之前觉得当街区监管员一定很好玩
I really thought being Block Captain would be more fun,
还以为能混把真枪或电击枪什么的呢
like I'd have a gun or a Taser or something.
而我现在只有这个哨子
All I get is this whistle.
别小瞧哨子
Don't knock the whistle.
哨子每年阻止几百宗罪案
Whistles stop hundreds of crimes every year.
喊停上千场篮球赛
And thousands of basketball plays.
还能让海豚跳出水面吃鱼
And they make dolphins jump out of the water and eat fish.
老爸  你也可以的
Dad, you could do that.
鲍勃  我记着你养的不是栗鼠就是小孩
Bob, I recall you raise either chinchillas or children.
是哪个来着
Which is it?
-小孩  -很好
- Uh, children. - Good.
我正在征集想法
I'm focus-testing some ideas.
我想在奇妙码头新建一个人气娱乐设施
I need a new blockbuster attraction at Wonder Wharf.
你怎么不去问问奇妙码头的那些孩子
Why don't you focus-test with the kids down at Wonder Wharf?
那群小绵羊吗  他们的钱我已经刮完了
Those sheep? I've already got their money.
而且  这几个孩子是美国年轻人的完美代表
Besides, these children are a perfect cross-section of American youth.
没错  男孩  女孩  和蒂娜
Yeah, boy, girl, and Tina.
我是潮流教主
I'm a tastemaker.
我一张口  众人跪听
When I talk, people listen.
你们几个
Guys?
费舍奥德先生
Mr. Fischoeder,
我们几个有瘾
we're adrenaline junkies.
我们喜欢纯度高  加工少
We like our rides pure, uncut,
在梅阔集装的货
and assembled in Meico.
我想抽点东西从这里  这里
I want something coming out of here, here,
还有/或者这里出来
and/or here.
完美抽脂的三洞标准
The three-hole standard of excellence.
等等  再给我指一下这三个洞
Wait, walk me through the holes again.
给你们看看参考例子
Let me throw some concepts at you.
满是果冻的蹦蹦房
A bounce house full of jelly.
果酱监狱
Jam Slam!
-试试酸辣酱  -接着说  巴纳姆
- Try chutney. - Keep pitching, Barnum.
恐怖木马
Scare-ousel,
这些木马都是死马骨架做的
a carousel where you ride on real horse skeletons.
说到"马"我挺感兴趣
You had me at "horse"
但是说到"死马骨架"我就不想听了
but lost me at "horse skeletons".
如果你想寻找人气题材
You know, if you're looking for an attraction,
这座小镇其实有段有趣的电影史
this town actually has some interesting movie history.
肥猪洗澡
Hog Wash!
没说你  鲍勃  这是一个点子
Not you, Bob, it's an idea.
和猪一起玩滑梯
Slide with the hogs.
这主意还不错
That's not bad.
好了  说真的  八十年代那会儿
Yeah, well, seriously, in the 80s,
有人在这座镇上拍了一部鲨鱼电影
they shot one of those shark movies right here in town,
《深海狂鲨3》
<i>The Deepening 3.</i>
对  是部3D电影
Oh, yeah, in 3D.
没错  3D的《深海狂鲨》
Right, the Deepening 3D-eepening.
那只鲨鱼害我非常怕水
Oh, that shark made me so scared of the water,
一整个夏天我都是站着尿尿
I spent the whole summer standing up to pee.
后来逐渐成了习惯
Then I got into the habit.
我喜欢这姿势
I like it.
靠她就能吸引大家
There's your attraction.
泰迪  你记得《深海狂鲨》吧
Teddy, you remember <i>The Deepening</i>, right?
何止记得  我还演过呢
Remember it? I was in it.
我们这些土著也有参演那部电影
Some of us locals worked on that movie.
我演的是英俊的3号救生员
I was handsome Lifeguard #3.
-真的吗  -真的假的
- Really? - Seriously?
是真的  怎么了
Yeah, what?
只是  我们看着眼前的你
It's just, uh, you know, we're looking at the "after".
实在难以想象以前的你
It's kind of hard to picture the "before".
鲍勃
Bob.
伙计们  有人在卖那只鲨鱼
Guys, the shark's for sale.
什么  那只鲨鱼
What? The shark?
有家道具室在卖那部电影的机械鲨鱼
A prop house is selling the actual mechanical shark
随时可以交易
and they're ready to deal.
是那条鲨鱼吗
The actual shark?
费舍奥德先生  你一定要买下那只鲨鱼
Oh, wow, Mr. Fischoeder, you've got to get that shark.
不  别  千万  别买
Nah, don't, no, come on.
泰迪  买嘛
Teddy, yes.
你还演过那部电影
You worked on the movie,
你应该感到兴奋才对
you should be excited about this.
是啊  但就是别提那条鲨鱼
Yeah, but just not that shark.
怎么了  泰迪
Why, Teddy?
我不想说
I don't want to talk about it.
好了  现在有一人完全赞同
Okay, that's one vote for yes
一人支吾反对
and one cryptic vote for no.
我们来问问意见小组吧
Let's run it past the focus group.
我身上有五个洞  算上两个鼻孔
Five-holer, nostrils, too.
听起来是你赢了
Sounds like a winner.
不
No!
泰迪  你到底怎么了
Teddy, what is wrong with you?
番茄酱没了
Uh, this ketchup is empty.
能再来一瓶吗
Can I get a new ketchup, please?
某些演员  比如这条鲨鱼  特别爱演
Some actor, this shark, a real ham.
它演起戏来比尼古拉斯?凯奇还要投入
He chewed more scenery than Nicolas Cage.
它吃掉的布景比尼古拉斯?凯奇还要多
它是真的吃了布景  用他那鲨鱼牙
He really chewed it... with his shark teeth.
-哈哈哈哈哈  -露易丝  别笑了
- Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha! - Louise, stop.
这位是殡仪馆的莫特  掌声感谢
Mort the mortician, everybody.
我看见了鲍勃?贝尔彻
Hey, I see Bob Belcher.
这主意就是他出的
All this was his idea.
你们心里一定想说
I know what you're thinking.
就他
That guy?
是的  就是这个  开食品店的
Yes, the guy with the, uh, food place.
谢谢  我们开的是餐馆
Thank you. It's a restaurant.
开心汉...
It's called Bob's...
现在  有请滑水冠军
Now, please welcome champion water skier
同时也是鲨鱼嘴下的幸存者
and shark attack survivor,
克里斯蒂・珊度琪
Kristi Sanducci.
我想谢谢那个
I'd like to thank the jackass
给我左手用剪刀的二货
who got the left-handed scissors.
感谢克里斯蒂・珊度琪
Kristi Sanducci.
她总是  这么专业
Always professional.
下面  有请3D版《深海狂鲨》的大明星
Now, the real star of <i>The Deepening</I> 3D-eepening,
他就是...鲨鱼
the... shark.
鲨鱼  好耶
Woo-hoo, shark, yeah!
岁月不饶人啊
Someone has not aged well.
你瞅它那张脸
What a butterface.
我们已经给它灌好油了
We've filled her up with diesel,
现在我们来看看它能做些什么
now let's see what she can do.
它在向我们摇尾巴  你好呀
It's waving at us. Hi!
这个杆是控制尾巴的
So that one does that.
再来看看这个杆是干嘛的
Let's see what this one does.
太棒了  谢谢你  上帝
Yes! Thank you, God.
按错了...这个...
Woop, wrong one... Oh, here we...
我的天
Oh, boy.
好了好了  就这样的
Yes, yes, all part of the fun.
可以把胳膊还给我不
Can someone pass my arm back up here?
拿过来  露易丝
Give me that, Louise,
我们得还给她
we've got to give it back.
没门  我接到了
No way! I caught it!
就像在婚礼上接到新娘捧花一样
It's like the bouquet at a wedding.
下一个被咬的就是我
I'm gonna get bit next!
很好玩吗
You having fun?
我没有  我...
I wasn't, I...
她用得还挺顺手的
Wow, she's good with that thing.
可以用来打人  也可以想放哪就放哪
She can do that and park anywhere she wants.
悲剧了
And so it begins.
我们干嘛要看假鲨鱼的电影
Why are we watching a movie about a fake shark
奇妙码头不就有一只真的假鲨鱼吗
when we could be at Wonder Wharf standing next to the real fake shark?
因为我想以这种方式怀念鲨鱼
Because this is how I want to remember the shark--
最精彩的地方就是它把琳达・布莱尔吓个半死
in its prime, scaring the crap out of Linda Blair.
美国女演员
费舍奥德一直开着鲨鱼真是太疯狂了
Fischoeder is crazy to keep that thing going.
那只鲨鱼已经咬掉了那个女孩的胳膊
After what happened to that girl's arm
咬死了那位夫人的小狗
and that lady's poor dog
咬下了那个男人的蛋蛋
and that guy's balls--
就是那个变戏法的
you know, the juggler.
是啊  费舍奥德真是太疯狂了
Oh, yeah, Fischoeder's crazy to keep it going
他让那么多人排队等候
with all those people lining up,
花钱观看  购买纪念品
paying to see it, buying souvenirs.
那只鲨鱼只会带来霉运
Nothing good can come from that shark.
它是魔鬼
It's evil.
我又出现了
Oh, there I am again.
穿红白蓝泳裤的就是我
That's me in the red, white, and blue trunks.
你们在看什么
What's everybody looking at?
-没什么  -没什么
- Nothing. - Nothing.
你的身体
Your body.
我的天啊
Oh, my God,
刚才琳达・布莱尔的胸部从湿的泳衣里弹了出来
Linda Blair's boobs just popped out of her wet suit.
直冲你来
Ooh! They're coming at you!
这部片子比我印象中的色一点点
Huh, this movie's a little bluer than I remember.
咱们看看好的地方
Let's get to a good part.
-室外沐浴戏  不  -看这个
- Outdoor shower scene. No. - Yes.
-裸身洗车戏  -看这个
- Topless car wash. - Yes.
蒂娜  不行
Tina, no.
-浴缸激情戏  -看这个
- Nude hot tub. No. - Yes.
-好了  看这段纯洁的鲨鱼戏  -不看
- Oh, okay, here's some good clean shark. - No.
看见那个被吃掉的冲浪者没
See that surfer getting eaten?
我跟她睡过
I made out with her.
她连戏妆都没卸
She had her movie makeup on.
道具内脏挂在体侧
Fake organs were coming out of her side.
非常诡异
Pretty weird.
八十年代的风格  对吧
The 80s. Am I right?
你说的没有错
You are not wrong.
鲨鱼为什么要攻击那艘潜水艇呢
Why is the shark attacking that submarine?
中情局训练鲨鱼攻击苏联潜水艇
The CIA is training sharks to attack Soviet subs,
他们抓了鲨鱼宝宝放在浴缸里做人质
and they're holding the shark's baby hostage in the nude hot tub.
这么说鲨鱼并不坏嘛
So the shark isn't bad.
它只是在保护孩子
She's just protecting her baby.
我们误会它了
She's misunderstood.
它只想有个朋友
She just needs a friend.
它不想待在这
It doesn't want to be here.
这根本就是剥削
This is exploitation.
我来告诉你什么是剥削
I'll show you exploitation.
爬上去把鲨鱼鳍给我割下来
Go up there and get me that fin.
你要割它的鳍
You want her fin?
我有个客户
I've got a guy.
他想要鱼鳍冰镇打包  马上空运过去
He wants it packed in ice and on the next plane.
他干嘛要一只机械鲨鱼的鳍
Why does he want a mechanical shark fin?
炖机械鲨鱼鳍汤
Mechanical shark fin soup.
听起来确实不错
Mmm, that does sound good.
别割掉它的鳍
Don't cut off her fin.
那是它最重要的特征
It's her best feature.
拜托  蒂娜  它还会长出来的
God, Tina, it'll grow back.
对哦  那你砍吧
Oh, yeah, cut it off.
我正在徒手骑鲨鱼
I'm barebacking a shark.
拜托  吉恩  快点把鳍割下来
Come on, Gene, chop-chop with the chop-chop.
它要翻了
Whoa, it's tippy!
不  吉恩  快割下鳍
Aah, no, Gene, get the fin!
这里安全吗
Are we safe here?
当然  这有隔离带呢
Of course! It's safety tape.
如果不能挡住东西那还叫什...
They can't just call it that if it's...
快逃  鲨鱼  快逃
Run, shark, run.
是我们放了它
We set it free.
不  不是我们  我们根本没来过这
No, we didn't, we were never here.
可我们明明来过
But we were.
现在想起来了吗
Remember right now?
是的  好了  你知道我又想起来什么了吗
Yeah, okay, but you know what I just remembered?
我们根本没来过这
We were never here.
好吧
Oh, okay.
我去  这电影有九成镜头都是裸身洗车
Man, this movie is, like, 90% nude car wash.
鲍勃  奇妙码头好像有些骚乱
Bob, there's some kind of commotion down at the Wonder Wharf.
好像西班牙的奔牛节  就是二了点
It's like the running of the bulls but dumber.
是的  不过这个是鲨鱼
Yeah, but with a shark.
没错  这个就是鲨鱼
Uh, yeah, it is a shark.
是啊  是鲨鱼
Yeah, it's a shark.
不必担心
Nothing to worry about.
就是鲨鱼出了点小问题
Having a little shark problem.
大家现在可以去买些热狗或者爆米花什么的
Uh, good time to grab a hot dog or some popcorn.
或者热狗什么的
Oh, or a hot dog.
费舍奥德先生  适可而止行吗
Mr. Fischoeder, enough's enough, right?
快点关掉那个鲨鱼  好吗
You've got to shut off the shark, right?
马上  关掉
I mean, now.
关掉  不不  游乐场里这么多人
Shut it off? Oh, no, no, I've got a packed park.
我不能关掉这个最受欢迎的设施
I can't shut down my top attraction.
我是说  我真的关不掉
I mean, I really can't.
油烧光了它才会停下来
That thing's on till it runs out of gas.
它要是窜出奇妙码头呢
But what if it breaks out of Wonder Wharf?
到时候要怎么办
What happens then?
那可是钢筋水泥砌的墙  鲍勃
Those are reinforced cement walls, Bob,
出自某位...自豪的移民之手
built by somebody... proud immigrants,
也许吧  我也不...
I guess, I don't...
怎么回...鲨鱼掉下来了
What...? The shark fell over?
太可怕了
That's crazy.
我们刚刚还在图书馆呢  对吧
We were at the library, right, guys?
对  在知识的海洋里畅游
Yeah, exploring the wonderful world of books and periodicals.
没错
Uh, yeah.
那还有微缩胶片
And microfiche.
不  不  不  不
Oh, no, no, no, no...
-该死  -我的天哪
- Crap. - Oh, my God!
鲨鱼跑到海洋大道上了
The shark's busted onto Ocean Avenue.
都是我的错
This is my fault.
我要负起责任
I have to do something.
啥
What?
我说  "都是我的错"
I said, "This is my fault."
"我要负起责任"
"I have to do something."
街区监管员鲍勃
Block Captain Bob.
没错
Yeah.
我去
God.
海洋大道的众多店主都担心
On Ocean Avenue, local merchants fear
奥尔森?奔纳
自己将会变成鱼食
they will become so much fish food,
而警察和消防员则陷入了一场
while police and fire officials are caught
领地划分战
in a surf-and-turf battle.
与此同时  当地居民正在自行设法应对
Meanwhile, local citizens are taking matters into their own hands.
街区监管员已经发起紧急会议
The Block Captain has called an emergency,
全体居民参加的阻止鲨鱼会议...
all-block, shark-stopping meeting...
那只鲨鱼毁了我的工艺美术品店
That shark is ruining my arts and crafts business!
这个小镇可以没有美术品
This town might do all right without arts,
但工艺品呢
but crafts?!
没有工艺品我们怎么活
Where the hell are we gonna be without crafts?!
去你妹的工艺品
Screw crafts!
我的酒品店要怎么办
What about my liquor store?
让我说几句
Let me talk!
大家伙  听我说  冷静冷静
Everybody, listen! Calm down!
你冷静冷静
You calm down!
-我爱子都没了  -真的吗
- I lost a son! - Seriously?
我爱的那床太阳被子  它真的很漂亮
A sun quilt. It was beautiful.
大家听着  问题会解决的
Listen, we're gonna solve this!
没错  大家都听鲍勃的
Yes, let's listen to Bob.
买鲨鱼这个主意就是他出的
He's the idea man behind the shark.
我的安全顾虑他完全不理  顺带说下
He pooh-poohed all my safety concerns, by the way.
-你说什么  -交给你了  我先走一步
- What? - Thank you. I have to run.
不  我说的是弄条机械鲨鱼会很棒
No, I said it might be cool to get a mechanical shark.
可它不是我放掉的
I didn't turn it loose.
-就是他  -不  不是我
- Yes, he did! - No, I didn't!
没人知道是谁弄的
Nobody knows who did!
就是  别再施加政治迫害了
Yeah, stop this insane witch hunt!
当时不在图书馆的都有嫌疑
It could've been anyone who wasn't at the library.
图书馆
The library?
这没用
It's no use!
他们知道鲨鱼是我们弄倒的
They know we knocked the shark over!
等等  什么  是你们弄的
Wait, what? You did?
当然不是  这只是种表达方式
No! That's just an expression.
今天你弄倒鲨鱼了吗
Hey, did you knock over the shark today?
你明知道我弄了
You know I did!
你们全家都他妈是极品
You're the family from hell!
他们快把小镇毁了
They're destroying the town!
赶紧召开镇级会议
Let's have a town meeting
商讨如何处置贝尔彻一家
to decide what to do with the Belchers!
泰迪  你在干什么
Teddy, what are you doing?
我想引起大家的注意
I'm trying to get everyone's attention,
可我没有指甲
but I don't have any nails.
好了  那你想说什么
Okay, so what do you want to say?
-我想说点什么  -嗯  你说
- I have something to say. - Yes. What?
我早说过别买那条鲨鱼
I told you not to get that shark!
我早说过它就是个麻烦
I told you he was trouble!
现在我们要齐心协力阻止它
Now we need to join together to stop him.
你没看到吗
Don't you see?
我们正在窝里斗
Us fighting with each other,
这正中它的下怀
that's what he wants!
泰迪  住手
Teddy, stop!
好了  泰迪  谢了  谢了
Yes, Teddy, thank you. Thank you.
所以我们要齐心协力阻止鲨鱼
So, yeah, we've got to join together to stop the shark.
大家一起想想办法好吗
Let's put our heads together, right?
街区监管员智力大考验
Block Captain brainstorm.
没有坏主意  走你
No bad ideas. Go.
像电影里那样  光着上身洗车
Topless car wash, like in the movie!
光着上...
Topless car...
这个就别记了
Don't write that down.
琳达说你没有坏主意的  鲍勃
Uh, Linda said there were no bad ideas, Bob.
那她错了  雨果
Well, she was wrong, Hugo.
可不  嫁给你的时候也是
Yes, like when she married you.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
我听到你嘟囔了
I heard you mutter something.
是啊  一个人嘟囔的时候
Yes, and when someone mutters,
往往都是在跟自己说话
that means they're muttering to themself.
-弥天大错  -好了我听到了
- Huge mistake. - Well, I heard you.
-什么  -我听到你嘟囔了
- What? - I heard you mutter.
是吗  我嘟囔什么了
Oh, really? What did I say?
"琳达犯了个弥天大错"
"Linda made a huge mistake."
说得太对了
So we agree.
其他人怎么说
Someone else?
听我说
Listen to me.
我知道鲨鱼的想法
I know how the shark thinks.
它很困惑
It's confused.
它不知道你们为什么要追杀它
It doesn't know why you want to kill it.
它只想回家
It just wants to go home.
蒂娜  它是一台机器
Tina, it's a machine.
它比我们的烤箱还傻
It's dumber than our toaster.
我们的烤箱也很困惑
Our toaster is also confused.
它不知道我们为什么要往它里面放百吉果
It doesn't know why we put bagels in it.
我的天
Oh, my God.
现在有四个好主意
Okay, we got four good ideas.
长条路钉  路面撒油  吊钩吊起  请君入洞
对  我们可以试上四次
Well, four Hail Marys we could try.
阻止鲨鱼
Let's stop the shark!
不要
Or not.
-阻止鲨鱼  -不要
- Let's stop the shark! - Or not!
- Let's stop the shark! - Or not.
既然长条路钉能够阻止耍酒疯的兄弟会会员
If a spike strip can stop those drunk Shriners,
那也应该能够阻止鲨鱼
it should be able to stop a shark.
它要过来了  它要过来了
Here it comes! Here it comes!
好啦  鲨鱼已经扎到钉子了
Okay, we've given the shark spikes.
我就知道会这样
I knew that would happen.
油会阻止鲨鱼乱动
That oil's gonna keep the shark from getting any traction.
我们帮它加速了
And we made it faster.
真不错啊  鲍勃
Bravo, Bob!
要想抓住鱼
You want to catch a fish,
就得像渔夫一样思考  对吧
you gotta think like a fisherman, right?
好了  这下鲨鱼触到电了
Okay, now the shark is electrified!
你这么做鲨鱼更有杀伤力了  鲍勃
All you're doing is making the shark more dangerous, Bob.
-我有眼睛  雨果  -我就提醒一下
- I can see that, Hugo! - It was an FYI.
鲍勃  鲨鱼离咱们餐馆越来越近了
Bob, the shark's getting pretty close to our restaurant.
没关系
It's all right.
绝招在最后  请君入洞
We've saved the best idea for last: the big hole.
为什么把绝招留在最后
Why'd we save our best idea for last?
因为在其他招数都失效前
Because we didn't know it was the best idea
谁也不知道这招就是绝招
until the other ideas were really terrible.
-蠢货  -反正
- Stupid. - Anyway,
我们挖个大洞  让鲨鱼掉进去
we dig a big hole, the shark falls in,
希望能够解决问题
and hopefully, end of our problems.
中国要麻烦了
Beginning of China's problems!
抱歉了  中国
Sorry, China!
他们会解决的  他们很聪明的
They'll nail it. They're really smart.
来啊  过来啊
Come on, keep going.
爬到洞里去  你这大老鼠
Climb into your hole, you big mouse!
快回去  这是个陷阱
Turn around! It's a trick!
你成功了  鲍鲍
Ah-ha-ha! You did it, Bobby!
鲨鱼死翘翘了
The shark is gone!
它死了  却永远活在我们心上
Gone, but not forgotten.
等等  这又是哪出戏啊
Wait, what are we talking about again?
你也许不是一头恐怖  肥腻  变态
Maybe you're not such a horrible, greasy, perverted,
卑鄙  俗气  肮脏  还令人作呕的猪
shabby, two-bit, filthy, disgusting pig.
行了行了  谢谢夸奖
All right, thanks, thanks.
那是什么
What was that?
那东西还在下面慢慢动着
That thing's still moving down there.
可是我们已经埋上它了
But we buried it.
我想它正在啃向我们的地下室
I think it just ate its way into our basement!
爸  我们能养着它吗
Dad, can we keep it?
鲨鱼真在咱家地下室
The shark is in our basement?
只有去一探究竟了
Well, there's only one way to find out for sure.
孩子们  待在这
Kids, stay here.
鲨鱼没进去之前
Yeah, I thought our basement was scary
我就觉得地下室很吓人了
before it had a shark in it.
鲍勃  别去  你已经尽力了
Bob, stop. You've done everything you can.
你不用非得下去
You don't have to go down there.
这个哨子命令我去
This whistle says I do.
那个哨子响了[在说大话]
That whistle blows!
废话少说
Enough talk.
现在做个了结
This ends now.
我和莫特陪你一起去  鲍勃
Mort and I will go with you, Bob.
什么  我是说  太好了
What? Oh, I mean, yes!
谢谢你们  真是帮了大忙
Thanks, guys. That means a lot.
告诉大家一个好消息
Oh, good news, everyone!
梦之队要出手了
The dream team's on it!
亚哈[以色列国王]  灰哈  松哈
Ahab, Gray-hab, and Flab-hab!
你想来吗  雨果
You want to come, Hugo?
我就不去了  我来调控人群
No, I'm good. Crowd control.
退后退后
Back up! Back up!
好安静  突然间
Real quiet, all of a sudden.
像停尸间一样安静
Quiet as a morgue.
实际上停尸间没安静到这种程度
Morgues aren't all that quiet, actually.
可能是燃气烧完了
Maybe it finally ran out of gas.
我们可以明天回去
We could come back tomorrow.
不  我们要确保它死了
No! We gotta make sure it's dead,
然后把它碎尸万段
and then we gotta cut it up in little pieces
这样它就不会再伤害人了
so it never hurts anyone again!
泰迪  冷静
Whoa, Teddy, calm down.
你和那只鲨鱼到底有什么过节
What happened with you and that shark, anyway?
对不起  鲍勃
Sorry, Bob.
你知道的  这是我和这只鲨鱼的私事
You see, it's personal between me and this shark.
我在那个剧组拍戏时
We had a little run-in,
我们之间起了些争执
back when I was working on that movie...
我当时正在和那个可爱的冲浪女孩调情
I was chatting up that cute surfer girl.
你就甭惦记了
Well, you can forget about getting any of this!
我本可以追到她的  鲍勃
She could've been the one, Bob!
从那之后我就开始暴饮暴食
I hit the craft service table pretty hard after that.
我就是从那个时候开始发胖的
That's when I started getting fat.
我不明白
Uh, I don't understand.
你为什么不冲鲨鱼操纵员生气呢
Why aren't you mad at the shark operator?
对啊  说得有道理
Oh, yeah, that's a good point.
不不  是鲨鱼在操纵他
No, no! The shark drove him to it.
它很邪恶  而我现在胖了
It's evil, and now I'm fat.
你也没那么胖啦  泰迪
You're not that fat, Teddy.
我穿着紧身腰带  这个叫妇男紧身褡
I'm wearing a guy girdle. It's called a Boydle.
你看我  你看我
Look at me. Look at me!
好了  泰迪  瞧  你看我
Okay, Teddy... Well, you know, look at me.
你好  泰迪  我是鲍勃的肚子
Hi, Teddy. I'm Bob's belly.
你真会安慰人  鲍勃
Oh, you always know what to say, Bob.
看这里
Over here!
我是莫特的肚子
I'm Mort's belly.
怎么
Huh? What?
不说这段子了吗
We're not doing that bit anymore?
里面怎么了
What's going on in there?
你们听到了吗
Did you guys hear that?
看来得换一个更大的餐馆了
Oh! We're gonna need a bigger restaurant!
-拜托  -抱歉
- Oh, come on. - Sorry.
坚持住  莫特
Hang on, Mort!
我还...不够...胖
Not... fat... enough!
莫特
Mort!
不  我想莫特被吃掉了
No! I think Mort got eaten.
他弄肚子的时候  我真应该多笑一笑
Oh, I should've laughed more at that belly-talking thing he did.
莫特  你还好吗
Mort, are you okay?!
我出来了  我是真的在抓吸管[救命稻草]
I'm out! I'm literally grasping at straws!
泰迪  你被咬碎了
Teddy, you're being crushed!
不  我的腰带保护了我
No, my Boydle's protecting me,
但我不知道这玩意能坚持多久
but I don't know how long it's gonna hold!
这就是你想要的  是不是
This is what you want, isn't it?
这就是你想要的
This is what you want!
我好心痛
I'm torn.
老爸养我长大  但是鲨鱼最懂我心
Dad raised me, but the shark gets me.
如果鲨鱼吃掉我们的餐馆
If the shark eats our restaurant,
它就是新老板喽
is he our new boss?
鲨鱼老板
Shark boss!
我晕过去了  鲍鲍
I'm blacking out, Bobby!
我不知道要怎么阻止它
I don't know how to stop it.
所有招数都用尽了
We've tried everything!
糟糕的是我们无法让它死于癌症
It's too bad we can't make it die from cancer,
就像电影演的那样
like in the movie.
它不是得癌死的  泰迪
It didn't die from cancer, Teddy.
对  你说得对
Oh, no, you're right.
他们也拍了癌症的结局
They shot the cancer ending,
但是试播的时候非常不好
but it tested really bad.
没有什么效果
It didn't have the "pow".
真的吗  癌症结局  没有效果
Really? Cancer? No pow?
是啊  他们又拍了一个新的结局  记得吗
Yeah, they shot a whole new ending, remember?
他们往它嗓子里灌稀水泥
They went and poured wet cement down its throat.
如果我们也有水泥搅拌器的话
Yeah, and that would be really helpful
那就帮大忙了
if we had a cement mixer!
这个可以有
Maybe we do.
冰淇淋机
The ice cream machine.
没错
She's right.
我们可以给鲨鱼灌上冰淇淋
We could fill up the shark with ice cream.
这样它就完蛋了  对吧
That might mess it up, right?
-我选你  老爸  -谢了  蒂娜
- I chose you, dad. - Thanks, Tina.
-去征服鲨鱼  -谢了
- Over the shark. - Thanks.
-因为我觉得...  -嗯
- Because I thought... - Yes.
-原本  我是想...  -嗯
- Originally, it looked like maybe I would... - Yes.
是啊  老爸  蒂娜究竟会选谁呢
Yeah, dad, who was Tina really gonna choose?
是眼神呆滞的没用废物
A broken-down wreck with the dead eyes,
还是假鲨鱼
or a fake shark?
这段子你喜欢吗  老妈
You like that, mom?
喜欢
Yeah.
好了  我来试试
Okay, let's give it a try.
我只需要把它插上
All I have to do is plug it in.
快点  鲍勃
Ow! Hurry, Bob.
有一些牙齿已经咬透腰带了
Some of the teeth are getting under the Boydle!
用力抻抻  鲍勃  用力抻
Stretch, Bob! Stretch!
你这也叫抻吗
You call that stretching?
插上了
Got it!
我的脚好凉
My feet are getting cold.
一定是冰淇淋
Must be making ice cream.
我的腰带掉了
Oh, my Boydle came off!
你咬住了我的腰带  可你没咬住我
You got my Boydle, but you don't got me,
你这鲨鱼
you shark!
管用哎
It's working!
鲨鱼缓下来了
The shark's getting all logy!
我曾做过这样的梦
I've had dreams like this.
-结束了  -不  鲍勃
- It's over. - No, Bob.
去死去死去死
Die! Die! Die!
现在结束了  不  它还没有死
Now it's over. No, it's not dead!
开玩笑的  大家伙  开玩笑的
Just kidding, everybody. Just kidding.
多么鲨鱼啊
How shark was it!
我还是觉得没整对
I still feel like I'm doing that wrong.
鲍勃
Whoa, Bob!
我喜欢你把这地方弄成这样
I love what you've done with the place.
听着  我要出去几天
Listen, I'm gonna be out of town for a while,
你要  坚持下去
but, uh, keep it up.
我们应该谈谈修缮费用...  好吧
Uh, we should talk about repairs for... No. Okay.
我会想你的  鲨鱼
I'm going to miss you, shark.
我也会想你的  冰淇淋机
Hmm, I'm gonna miss you, too, ice cream machine.
他的死法真是令我神往
He died the exact way I want to go:
毁掉这个餐馆
destroying the restaurant.
我们要怎么把这鬼东西冲下厕所
Hey, how the hell are we gonna flush this thing down the toilet?
有人丢了腰带
Whoa, somebody lost their Boydle!
现在是我的了
It's mine now.
我的小小街区监管员鲍鲍
Ah, my little Bobby Block Captain.
你救了整个小镇
You saved the town.
应该的
Eh, just part of the job.
你被炒了
You're fired!
这并不全是我的功劳  奥尔森
I can't take credit for everything, Olsen,
即时新闻
逃亡鲨鱼停住了
不过作为四分之一街区监管员  我接受表彰
but as Quadrant Captain, I will.
不用谢
You're welcome.
谁想喝汤
Who wants soup?